A Guide to the William Martin Johnson Papers, 1937-1968
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
William Martin Johnson Papers, 1937-1968
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1982-017
0.6 cu. ft. 3 boxes
The papers in this collection include both personal and professional correspondence, ranging from November 1931 to March 1977. Johnson wrote to representatives at Public Works, American Society of Civil Engineers, the Department of Architectural Engineering at Virginia Polytechnic Institute, and the War Assets Administration, among others.
Johnson, William Martin
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
William M. Johnson graduated with B.S. in Civil Engineering in 1928 from Virginia Polytechnic Institute. He went on to work as a Civil Engineer for Wiley and Wilson, consulting engineers in Lynchburg, Virginia.
Scope and Content
The papers in this collection include both personal and professional correspondence, ranging from November 1931 to March 1977. Johnson wrote to representatives at Public Works, American Society of Civil Engineers, the Department of Architectural Engineering at Virginia Polytechnic Institute, and the War Assets Administration, among others. His letters discuss matters related to Civil Engineering. There are two photographs: one of Virginia Episcopal School, and one of Longwood College in Farmville, Virginia. This collection also features issues of The Newcomen Bulletin for North America from January 1963 to May 1973.
Arrangement
The William Martin Johnson Papers is organized in three series by material type. Series I: Correspondence includes personal and professional correspondence to and from Johnson between 1937 and about 1977. The majority of the letters relating to civil engineering topics. Series II: The Newcomen Bulletin for North America contains a collection of bulletins dating between 1963 and 1973. This series includes most, if not all, issues between 1963 and 1969, as well as scattered issues between 1970 and 1973. Series III: Papers and Ephemera consists of reports, newspaper clippings, photographs, and other personal papers.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Science and Technology; University Archives; University History; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1932-1977, n.d.
  - Nov. 17, 1932-Dec. 16, 1936 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Jan. 18, 1937-Dec. 18, 1937 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Jan, 12, 1938-Dec. 20, 1939 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Jan. 1, 1940-May 16, 1940 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - June 5, 1940-April 12, 1944 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - May 23, 1944-April 1, 1947 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - April 7, 1947-Sept. 25, 1947 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Oct. 9, 1947-Nov. 21, 1949 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Jan. 3, 1950-June 13, 1951 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - June 20, 1951-Mar. 7, 1952 (Box-folder 2-1)
  - Mar. 18, 1952-Oct. 8, 1952 (Box-folder 2-2)
  - Oct. 15, 1952-Jan. 9, 1961 (Box-folder 2-3)
  - Sept. 15, 1961-March 28, 1977 (Box-folder 2-4)
  - Undated (Box-folder 2-5 to 2-6 (2 folders))
- Series II: The Newcomen Bulletin for North America, 1963-1973
  - Jan. 24, 1963-Dec. 5, 1963 (Box-folder 3-2)
  - Jan. 17, 1964-Dec. 3, 1964 (Box-folder 3-3)
  - Jan. 28, 1965-Dec. 2, 1965 (Box-folder 3-4)
  - Jan. 20, 1966-Dec. 1, 1966 (Box-folder 3-5)
  - Jan. 20, 1967-Dec. 7, 1967 (Box-folder 3-6)
  - Jan. 25, 1968-Dec. 5, 1968 (Box-folder 3-7)
  - Jan. 23, 1969-Dec. 4, 1969 (Box-folder 3-8)
  - Jan. 22, 1970-May 23, 1973 (Box-folder 3-9)
- Series III: Papers and Ephemera
  - Reservation Coupons and Papers (Box-folder 3-1)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Letter from Nixon (Box-folder 3-10)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 3-11)
  - "Three Historic Documents of the Washington Family" Folder (Box-folder 3-12)
  - "Environmental Considerations Related to the Army Package Power Reactor" (Box-folder 3-13)